gzip a lossless file compression tool famous for making large chunks of data
gzip 一种无损文件压缩工具，以使大量数据
smaller the files on a computer are represented by bits on a silicon chip
变小而闻名计算机上的文件由硅芯片上的位表示，
but they often take up more space than is actually necessary for example when
但它们通常占用比实际需要的空间更多的空间，例如当
you write your screenplay in a text document you produce a bunch of repeated
您在文本文档中编写剧本时
patterns many years ago computer scientists realized we were wasting
许多年前，计算机科学家意识到我们在浪费
space and wrote algorithms like lz77 to address this problem by looping over the
空间并编写了类似 lz77 的算法来解决这个问题，通过循环
contents of a file to identify repeated sequences that can be replaced with
文件的内容来识别可以用
metadata or shorter sequences thus reducing the total amount of bits
元数据或更短的序列替换的重复序列，从而减少总的重复序列。 表示信息所需的位数
required to represent the information most importantly no information is lost
最重要的是不会丢失任何信息
this differs from lossy compression algorithms like jpeg which can make an
这与 jpeg 等有损压缩算法不同，jpeg 可以使
image file smaller but information is lost in the process gzip was developed
图像文件更小但在此过程中会丢失信息 gzip
by jean-luc guys and mark alder in 1992 because the big evil tech corporations
由 jean-luc guy 和 mark alder 在 1992 年开发，因为 大邪恶科技公司
held the patents on existing compression technology their implementation is based
持有他们实施的现有压缩技术的专利 ntation
on the deflate compression algorithm which is a combination of lz77 and
基于 deflate 压缩算法，它是 lz77 和
huffman coding gzip is not the only game in town and other formats like zip 7zip
霍夫曼编码的组合 gzip 不是城里唯一的游戏，其他格式如 zip 7zip
and rar solve similar problems on the web gzip is the most common way to
和 rar 解决了网络上的类似问题gzip 是实现端到端的最常见
implement end-to-end compression where a file is compressed on the server then
方式 - 结束压缩，其中文件在服务器上
decompressed by the browser to reduce the amount of data sent over the network
压缩，然后由浏览器解压缩以减少通过网络发送的数据量，
although broadly is a newer compression algorithm that's generally superior for
尽管广义上是一种较新的压缩算法，通常更适合
files on the web to get started open up any linux machine where you'll find gzip
网络上的文件开始打开任何 linux 机器 您会发现 gzip
installed by default as one of the most popular utilities of the gnu project to
默认安装为 gnu 项目最流行的实用程序之一来
compress a file use the gzip command followed by the file name that creates a
压缩文件使用 gzip 命令后跟文件名，该文件名创建一个
new file ending in gz that should be significantly smaller run the command
以 gz 结尾的新文件，该文件应该明显更小再次运行该命令
again with the l flag to print out the compression ratio the higher the ratio
l 标志打印出压缩比
the more space that was saved now use the d flag to decompress the file back
比率越高，节省的空间越多 现在使用 d 标志将文件解压
to its original form or better yet use the gunzip command in the real world
缩回其原始形式或 b 仍然在现实世界中使用 gunzip 命令，
though you'll often want to compress multiple files at the same time gzip on
尽管您经常希望同时压缩多个文件 gzip
its own cannot compress an entire directory for that you'll need to bring
本身无法压缩整个目录，因为您需要
in an archiver like tar its name is derived from tape archive and what it
引入像 tar 这样的存档器，它的名称是派生的 从磁带存档，它的
does is take multiple files and combine them into a single file known as a
作用是在运行 tar 命令时获取多个文件并将它们组合成一个称为
tarball when running the tar command include the z flag to automatically
tarball 的文件包括 z 标志以自动
compress the archive congratulations you just made a large set of files smaller
压缩存档 恭喜您刚刚使大量文件变小
this has been gzip in 100 seconds hit the like button if you want to see more
这是 gzip  100秒内点击喜欢按钮，如果你想看更多这样的
short videos like this thanks for watching and i will see you in the next
短片谢谢收看，我会在下一个看到你
one